long service recognition, we have 20 years, 15 years, 10 years, five years
commitment in Zyman's Korea. So thanks for that we have maintained this great business. Until now,
we will also give a short moment to appreciate on their work. And last but not least, we have
Stephanie Frank, who will be leading us from next fiscal year. And we would like to also hear from
her vision, her ambition, and how
what?
Thank you.
want to work together in next fiscal year and then we will invite all our four
speakers to the stage and take this opportunity to exchange our ideas and
questions and discuss openly so also colleagues joining from the teams or so
yeah don't hesitate to leave your questions or your opinions in the chat
we will take
up at the end in the q a session all right that's all from my side maybe you are looking forward to
seeing somebody else than me let's give him a big applause to welcome scott gardener on the stage
so um chunachim i if i got it right good morning and uh it's great to be here in korea um i have to
say uh
to be here at a time at the end of the year when you're going to be handing over from
tino to stephanie is certainly something um that was a great opportunity and why i really wanted
to come at this time what i'm going to just take you through though over the next 10 minutes or so
is one a little bit about you and the fact that we in headquarters
we very much appreciate everything you've done here in korea particularly you know
This last year, you have had an exceptional year.
So I'm going to cover a little bit about, and I'm going to give you a little bit about
what we're doing overall in sales and the changes we're making and why we're making
some of those changes and how that is now going to go through all of DI, because DI
is going through a larger change overall.
And I'll cover a little bit on that and then take a look forward as to what's next, what's
coming, what do we need and how.
you can be very much part of that and the spirit we want from everybody around the world
so firstly I want to say thank you it's as simple as that you guys have done an amazing job you've
had a fantastic year you have clearly outperformed the market and whether it was in the business
review we had yesterday with Timo and Frank or whether it was in the individual
channel reviews we had today, there is some great success this year. And I think that is
it's recognized and it's particularly recognized with how you picked up on the transformation
that is happening in semiconductor. Obviously, we have the Hynix opportunity.
Werner von Siemens Award winner nominee.
And it's a great example because I think it's part of the spirit
of what makes Korea a unique opportunity.
It's not just DI.
It's DI and SI.
It is at the very leading edge of some of our technology,
and it is taking that forward into what is an initial project
but has huge long-term.
implications for us in terms of the success of our business and we're not only a customer of
we're not only a provider to sk hynix but they're an important customer for us
right important provider to us and increasingly as we move forward we
I think we'll see more of their products inside some of our products, and you have helped enable
that as we drive forward into the engine. And I think that's...
a big chance of what i would say to everything that tino has done with you as the team over the
last four years is you've put in place a very strong foundation of operational integrity
diversification of your business into a broader range of verticals which
we discussed this morning and really setting this business up for being
able to leverage the growth that Korea, we believe, will go on over the next few years.
So, thank you.
What I also wanted to say, though, is we're changing.
You've been through a period of change.
You've been through a period of, you've been through a period of, of.
diversification yourselves. But DI is now going through a broader change. Last year, we made the
change on sales. So we brought together all sales into one organization. And that's about how we
become more customer effective and more customer centric.
But also at the same time, this year, we're now going to apply the same strategy to both the technical side of our business, the R&D and development side, and also the supply chain management and the manufacturing.
So we're going to put together not only a single sales organization, but there.
will be one di it will be one organization rather than being four individual business units there'll
be a single technical organization doing research and development a number of technology units within
it and obviously tino is going to be leaving one leading one of those in his new role
but actually how we bring together all of our technology and make sure all of our technology
works better together. And that's a key aspect because increasingly, I'm sure you see when you
go and talk to customers, customers don't want to talk about individual products anymore. They want
to talk about how we bring things together and how we make things work together more effectively
for them. And our...
changes are about making sure that from a research and development and also from a technology
perspective, we're enabling that in the same way as we're putting together one face to the customer
as we've done in sales. And we're going to do the same with manufacturing as well. In fact,
the manufacturing teams have already started on that work so that we can be more effective,
more efficient, and also deliver more of what the customers are asking for.
so that's our change but you've probably also heard under the terminology of one tech company
from roland that siemens is also going through our change some changes and siemens is going
through a change to what's called functionalization so increasingly you'll
look at things like marketing and marketing will be for the whole of siemens
increasingly, you look at P&O, and P&O will be for the whole of Siemens. But you'll also have heard
about some changes for sales as well, because we've introduced a new organization called
Foundational Sales. And I just wanted to give you a couple of moments on that, because some of our
team, particularly from the Headquarter Sales Organization, will now move to a Siemens level.
And the idea is, because it's not just being able to bring together more of the AI that our
customers.
want they want to be able to our customers want us to be able to bring together more of di
si software advanta and to do that more effectively and sfs and what
foundational sales is about is about bringing together all the systems data and processes
so that you can more seamlessly do that right across Siemens we can see our customer as one
organization set right through all of the different parts of Siemens and it doesn't mean we won't have
separate sales units because we still will there'll still be DI there'll still be SI buildings there's
still be EP and EA but
sales units will increasingly use common systems and processes more effectively so that we can
talk to customers as one siemens not just different organizations not having the same view of the
customer every time so i just wanted to highlight that because increasingly that will show up in the
systems and processes that exist for all of the regions including korea so what's next
so as we look in
to 27 for um di automation i think you know what do we expect um one i think it should be no
surprise and you did it this year is to continue robust growth
We talk about being a tech company at Siemens.
Tech companies grow double digit every year.
And so there is an expectation for robust growth
continuing to 2030 across our businesses and business lines.
We also expect to see, you know, quite a lot of portfolio change as we go through the next few years.
Increasingly, automation within it will have more software.
And we were discussing that earlier with regards to our partners and the partner channel.
Increasingly, we will have more software.
A number of you may have already been using the automation agent Eigen.
Aigen, we learned today, just passed our sales targets for fiscal year 26.
This is a hugely successful product out of the box.
AI, software, hand in hand with our core automation products.
And that trend will continue for us.
Increasingly, we will have more software and more AI in our portfolio.
But we'll also take advantage of being more competitive because we'll use things like AI ourselves.
Now, it's not going to be easy because the market conditions actually at the moment are complicated.
We have a lot of political volatility.
But I think if you think about our organization and you think about the changes we're making and we've just discussed.
Pulling together great people, stronger focus on customers with more integrated tools and processes and technology that is designed to work together.
We have an opportunity to be the industrial tech company for the world.
And career is one of those core markets where this will happen first.
So my big question message I want to leave you with is when you think about what we need to do going forward.
This is our slogan, dare to be bold.
Don't think of politics
between different parts of our organization.
It's about data.
Use information, use transparency, use systems
to help us make smart decisions internally
and to support our customers better.
sure you use shared values across our organization because actually that is the heart of what makes
Siemens successful respect each other standards every aspect of what we're doing because that
is ultimately what helps us be more successful
Entrepreneurial spirit, you know, if every one of us thinks of this business as being its own business, it's really what helps drive us forward.
If this was your business, would you do it?
That should be a question that we should ask ourselves every day when you're making every single decision.
Just make sure that that you're being customer first.
That is always, I think, the heart of what I say.
There's a.
a hierarchy of how you should think of decisions you're making in the entrepreneurial way and it's
customer
shareholder, self. If you think in that order, you're probably going to make the right decisions.
And then obviously the one tech company is going to be a big change for Siemens,
but it's how we bring it all together. So dare to be bold, look forward. And I look forward to
standing here again at some point into the future and congratulating you all again on another
fantastic year, maybe with a new leader in Stephanie, but I look.
to that as well so thank you for this year and thank you for the future because we're really
looking forward to it thank you scott yes we also look forward to another success year and years
ahead and have you back here in korea very good then oh sorry i'm sorry i revealed already that
your first opening slide please tino come to your page kind of
your last webcast for this fiscal year on this year and also yeah there's always a first and
the last one right so uh being in a company as siemens we're going through constant change right
we go through change in the country and many of you are having a different job and definitely
every of you has now a different organization right than what we have started with four years
ago right and sometimes the change brings you back to where you're coming from and for me it's time
to make the move but i will talk about this in a very minute
Scott, thank you for your sharing on the global perspective on the changes, but also in particular for highlighting the successes that are being delivered out of Korea and the big move you have made.
And it would be too easy to say, hey, the time the market collapsed, our business went down and the time the market is recovering, our business is going up.
I have to say it's a bit more complicated or actually much better because when the market went down.
have been down slower when the market came up we are up better than the market and this is a
combination of two things that i will get you through in the next few minutes
that you have delivered on the one side
We have been together, we have been spent a significant focus on ensuring the big deals that are going on in Korea, the mega investments.
And Scott said it, right?
We are one of the countries having all that leading technologies here.
And if you think about that, there is no vertical where Korea has not.
A local hero, a company that is among the top three worldwide.
Take automotive, semiconductor, shipbuilding, battery, whatsoever, right?
We're having the world leader, the world second or the third leader in that country.
And you leveraged their large investments over the years.
But on the other hand...
looking what we have done in a market that is dominated heavily by japanese technology
fano and mitsubishi we have developed customers that were 20 30 years if i look to hanway aerospace
if you look to ugentech for instance right they have been in the hand of our competitors for
more than two three decades and suddenly we turned it around and this together that made
the success of this organization and this is not coming by me and frank saying something new right
this is something how you took our direction and how
we brought it into action as the management team the team leads and for us most important each
individual in the channels in the old days in the views now in the zone and in the sack
organization and then of course also with everyone who's supporting us i'm looking around i'm not
seeing only people who having the i.o code i see people from the corporate functions i see people
from the country and from the zone and that's the big difference right you might remember we
introduced a year ago
Not anymore calling it DI Korea.
We started to call it DI in Korea.
And this goes beyond the organization, right?
This goes beyond the Orko.
This is all of you and happy to see you all again.
And it's great for having this final, my final webcast with all of you together.
So Scott already said it.
One of the highlights this year, and I would like to go again into this, is definitely the win of the SK Hynix project.
And this is something that's important from an approach because we were working on that.
over four years and everyone was challenging at the beginning why you spend so much effort
on something when nothing is coming back we said this is the ever largest semi-investment
we will see in that country and probably uh in the world right uh at one point at least
It takes time to get it.
It takes time.
We brought Cedric there, Roland there, Achim was there,
Noraina was there, Achim was other customers, right?
But we had them.
You were there with teams, with workshops, with tech days.
We did everything we can, and now we materialize it.
For me, it's not only to win things, right?
For me, it's also to talk about.
And we always told you, do good things and talk about.
And it became, meanwhile, a kind of...
regular approach that over the last three years, it was, I think, three times in a row, Frank,
right? Korea is within the finalists nominated within one of the categories at the Werner von
Siemens Award at the Siemens Business Conference. And we were so proud seeing it again. And I was
actually in big doubt that we get it because, you know, who was orchestrating the global customer
category for Werner von Siemens Award this year was Eugene, right? And I was thinking, oh, if the
coordinator comes from Korea, they will definitely not get our project in, right? But it was done so
nude.
so unbiased that we had a chance again to get in there and this is your success and the few people
who have the chance to come with us to munich right are representing all of you and it's one
project but it stands for all the projects we have secured over the last years and particular in this
year which is a one that is very strong and i will come to this in a minute but there is definitely
more than sk heinix it's just the one that is now again the flag of korea that we are showing on the
global stage but they have so much more and it's across
All the industries across all the channels, it's with customers we have very strategic relationships with.
And it's great.
I mean, Steffi, we have been working together for the Korean business, not just since you arrived.
We do this since four years or even longer.
And with D&Solution, you know, as a very strategic, one of the world's largest manufacturer of machine tool systems,
we are working together.
And this year, it really paid off.
The years of investments, Steffi, a couple of times here, meeting in Germany, meeting in Korea, meeting in China, meeting in the U.S.,
I'm coming.
over. We have met with Cedric and W.J. Kim, the CEO of the company. And finally, the business
takes up. Sometimes it takes, but then it pays back. SK, we talked about, there's not only SK.
If you look how also now we're materializing Samsung, all the efforts the team spent into
Samsung are now really coming back. And we have, you know that, right? In March this year,
reached a very major milestone and a big commitment with Samsung that VR approved
supplying spare parts until 2060.
68, 42 years from now, we are the part for supporting their maintenance efforts and remembering
the meetings we had, right?
The very first is four years ago, where I was hit for one hour by them because they
complained about our strategy.
We fixed it, and now we got a deal until 68, which is a very big achievement.
But also UginTech, and UginTech is one of the customer I take as an example for competitor
conversion.
It was in the hand of Mitsubishi over 20 years.
The other one is Hanoveros Bay, 30 years.
And at the end, the first year, the team came up with a business that was about 700,000 euros, so a bit above a billion Korean won.
The second year was, I think it was four-ish something.
And this year, by now, we have already over 8 million euros, which goes into 12 to 14 billion Korean won, depending on the currency exchange.
So this is how we scale a customer.
And the important topic is we did not do this alone.
It was done in strong collaboration.
with our partner. Without them, we could not really do this because they are handling the daily
operation with the customers and we are doing the strategic part, placing our portfolio. This also
shows how important is trying a collaboration between Siemens, the partners, and our customers.
So a very successful outcome in these areas over the last years,
what I am particularly very proud on, on what you have delivered.
And there is another aspect that we may not forget.
And you have seen it in one of the priorities in Scott Slides, PI, Process Industry's lifecycle business.
What is lifecycle business?
You enter a customer with a technology or with an approach, and then you scale the in-store base that you're having.
You're extending at the customer, you're upgrading the customer, and you're monetizing the portfolio you have delivered to that customer already.
And there is an example that you can be heavily proud on, and it's all about Merck.
And you know, last year at SBC, the Merck project, the initial one,
was also the nominee of the finalists at Werner von Siemens Award
in the customer category.
We didn't make it because if mobility is in, it's always difficult
because the whole mobility world always votes for them.
So just this year, please promote to everyone you know to Merck
to vote for SK.
But the Merck project was one we strategically decided
to do project business, what we actually don't even have.
It was the Cretus headquarters.
We entered the market.
We entered the pharmaceutical industry.
And this year, there was another opportunity where the Merck
Needs to be extended on the lifecycle side.
We have had a chance to get into the MES and ITOT integration topics.
And the team in Korea worked so hard.
And the team in Korea ensured that Merck in Korea is choosing Siemens as a supplier for this technology.
And then.
work decided to not work with a system integrator from korea they decided to work with the system
integrator from germany because it's a company based in germany to a high part and they have
their supply chain there
didn't give up and created him continue to work even knowing it will not be booked here it will
not be recognized in their sales performance and this for me makes a difference right they secure
the project allowed the german si to implement and siemens germany the rc to sell it to the customer
And this is something they will not see particular in their results at the end of the day this year.
I want that they see that we are seeing it.
And I want you to give a big hand, a big applause to the four colleagues who were mainly involved.
Oite, our master of pharmaceuticals, is here, right?
Come in front of me quickly.
Sang Ming on the technical support.
H.E.N. on the engineering.
And JolQ on technical sales.
I think three people should be here today, right?
Who is here of the names?
only one then it's always representing this thank you very much i mean it's standing in front of
scott and and sharing this success uh it's i think really great and it's a recognition we
wanted to give you don't give up uh it's a great value to generate it for siemens if it's been
done in korea or by a german company should not matter for us uh and please keep fighting on on
merck and all the pharma industry uh when you started we've been at zero right and now it's
a it's it's a double digit million euro business already what you generated
you
with my own great leadership.
Thank you very much.
Okay.
Thank you.
Really, really, really great, really great success what you have delivered.
So, and you know, we're always starting a year with giving directions, right?
We're giving directions on a higher level, allowing you to find a way on going forward.
And I quickly want to get you through.
We have set our strategic priorities for this fiscal year in order to reach a growth higher than the market.
We wanted to have 5% points more than what the market allows us.
Thank you.
And I talked about
Done. Checkmark. You did it. I talked about the new industries. We spoke about life science, for instance. We are in data center. You've done it. It's very good. We said we want you to look into monetizing install base and, for instance, going into Crane. Crane is next to Semiconductor this year, the second largest vertical that we are serving in a way how we contribute Siemens business.
Right. It's exceptionally well done. Congrats on that. And then, of course, also, we wanted to strengthen the base business with partners.
machine builders and machine tools and i think uh g1 still remembers that i'm always saying we
don't want to sell one machine right we want to sell the product into a thousand machines a
machine maker is doing in the repetitive business and you made it and also would like to give you
here a check mark very well done exceptional outcomes reached also on the enablers i mean
the new setup i think it took us some time it took us half a year but now we are in it works good
Good collaboration with the zone.
I see this in all the areas.
The new portfolio, I mean, we heard it from Scott Eigen as one of an example on how we're using AI, but also in Korea, we have a lot of AI success.
And for me, you know, over the time, it was always important to give focus on you, on the people, enable you.
And I'm leaving with a good feeling on that.
And I hope you are seeing it the very same way.
We have made a major step forward.
And also with that, a big thanks to Char.
I saw you somewhere.
For supporting us on the people's side, I really, really appreciate it.
and stay a strong partner to the eye in future as well.
So with that said, and Scott said it already, right,
the year will be exceptional.
So we have had our one-time highs.
We had the crash with the battery business disappearing.
And then we are slowly recovering
and we are bringing the eye career this year
to be assumed forecast on 308 billion Korean won
to a new high, to a new baseline.
And what Steffi will have the pleasure then
to, of course, continue with you
and drive this to, as Scott said,
to the next level.
of growth and asset the market does allow us i'm sure we're having the best team to materialize this
and bring it to reality and looking forward to see those numbers from a little distance then
but of course keeping always an eye on korea and the success that we are having and the way we have
transformed the organization is also reflected in the results we're getting from you right so sks
has improved again i mean participation rate was 77 without having strong push for me it's a very
good level knowing be coming from
below 40 right uh but also that the pnps so the score you are saying you promote the company has
again developed by plus 13 we are not on the level we're feeling well as a management so please keep
talking to us keep talking to your teams to your team leaders what is needed for you to even get
us to a new high but we have over four years every year a constant positive development what i would
like to really uh highlight here and thank you for this and for me always important that we are
turning feedback into actions you know every time after
sgs we're doing team workshops department workshops di workshops and sgas meetings
uh the sls meetings on talking on this and also here uh we took some feedback from you and
specifically learning that you even wish more skill development on artificial intelligence
what is the right question because this is what makes us strong uh the team around uh jisong who
is our learning manager together with char and her team have already worked on the next wave of
ai learning sessions for you to enable you better for what you actually
expecting from us so this is also going forward um and with that said i think it's time for frank
to give us a few financial insights
여러분 안녕하세요.
When I saw we have 15 minutes, Tino and myself, we are already five minutes over.
And now the finance part.
No, thank you.
Time management was never our strength here.
So finance, we make it very crisp and clear.
Unfortunately, I cannot show any figures because we are still in the silent period.
So I just show a couple of waves.
And the waves, everybody already knows this already.
The blue wave is order intake.
The green one is revenue.
And below, we have the order backlog.
So, coming now, what Tino said, the success stories and what we did over all the years, you see the waves are finally going in the right direction and they're going up and up and up every quarter.
As of now, we will most probably reach the highest and the best quarter in DI Korea so far.
We had this morning with Mio, we talked about the Merck project, we talked about a couple of revenue topics, super preparation in that regard.
So, we will end up the year quite...
good. The next one, this is basically our checklist. And we do this every quarter in all of
our town hall meetings. I even show this to Rudy and Cedric. Cedric is really happy, especially with
the development and the tendencies. I will not give now the full tendency for Q4 because we are
not done yet. However, what I can say, sales or the intake top line might be green as a tendency.
Productivity, yellowish, greenish. I think he also brought the curve up.
we have our ap zone meeting and now and scott also with the di transformation i think we was
a little bit bumpy road bumpy start so to say which is natural not yet okay technology now
who's checking uh so the di zone i mean from more from you work in the zone finally um and
locally i think this this is also uh getting great
ai and people tino mentioned that we are also doing an sgas follow-up in our case our famous
walk and talk with my finn colleagues half a day and we are following up on action um and last but
not least of course and this is one of the most important things no compromise on books and
compliance and here we of course this is a constant action item what we need to
where we need to focus on so and then last but not least
we have 17 days to go until the end of the physical year we are in the final lap now
as usual on the left side our driver this is tino i'm trying to keep the balance here
in order not that the motorcycle turns around and thank you very much tino really appreciate i mean
was a great joyride so to say for four years um really appreciate learned a lot from from you i
think the guidance the leadership
uh also friendship uh i would like to say really appreciate that was a was a great experience
and also then for next first of october onwards maybe we change with si a couple of with the ai
a couple of faces then all right thank you very much for that
thank you
you thank you frank and uh yeah also i i can give this back um first of all frank thanks for
being a good partner uh over the nearly four years we worked together right uh you started
shortly after me on on the di uh thin position but we have worked from day on one onwards also
as a cfo for the company very closely ensuring we're getting business in the way we want to have
it um as frank said learning from each other is something i also said yesterday to the management
team i learned a lot from you
i'm leaving as a different person than i came uh in a very positive way right with a lot of even
more knowledge than what what the regions need uh what the global organizations have to do in order
to enable you where we have to be looked at and how we have to give you power and that's also
something i will take within my new role and scott already said it right on the global side now as a
head of a technology unit for services uh i will definitely look and ensure that everything we are
doing has one aim making you successful serving our customers and securing business for the
company
I would also like to take the moment to thank you all for four great years together.
I mean, if you're looking at these pictures that you're seeing here,
these are actually almost all customer activities, right?
And I made a joke yesterday.
Obviously, half of my time I was standing on stages in front of customers like this, right?
But that's the way I'm talking, right?
That's the way I'm presenting.
But it was amazing to see how you perform not only when you're here.
in our holy halls it was for me very impressive to see how you perform when we go to a customer
then i can really see what sales power means and and and how your heart is beating and how you're
motivated and even the toughest meetings which we prepared sometimes four weeks to get there right
and not got shot at the very first moment we went through and as a team we've been strong
and at the end of the day whatever it was be it the technical difficulties we had in
the battery business be it the recent fires we had in the marines right uh
you all
always left with a stronger customer relationship and the customer at the end confirmed they all
have problems the difference is who fixes them and we are the partner who fixes them to them
and this is what the partner the customers really appreciate so keep this up that cannot be a
problem too difficult if you approach it in the right way if you
solve it and then strengthen your relationship with the customer that helps you of course also
to strengthen your business and with that picture i would like to uh leave it uh it's time for
another chapter for me
And for you, and I would like to once again thank you all for having me, for accepting me, for allowing me to drive you, getting the business there.
And later on, we are handing over to Stephanie.
I mean, this is now the final handover town hall.
But before we are doing this, Frank and I would like to do also jointly a final recognition and looking at the sales award and, of course, also to the long service award.
May Frank come to me.
This makes my life.
a little bit easier in this regard because he's much better in pronouncing the names than I.
Four years, 20 years. I mean, there must be a difference, right? And again, looking to the
sales performance for Scott and for Steffi and for Sarah, we're always looking in a quarter who
did the best performance in terms of a combination of growth, achievement, and so on and so forth,
right? And this time, we have quite a good group of people who achieved the KPIs we have been
setting and let's get them all here. If they aren't.
otherwise online, right?
So it's Pimsi-Yon.
Yon-Yon.
Pimsi-Yon.
Sihan.
Yeah.
Youngso is here, Youngwon from Insight Sales, Dongwo and Youngwon again.
Yeah, the other two are joining from Jongwon, yes.
It's always good to see that at least half of people are the customers, right?
But give them a big hand.
There is also a award voucher connected, what you will receive very officially later.
And this is your stage and your moment.
Thank you very much, colleagues.
Thank you.
Okay, thank you very much.
And last but not least, it has been already celebrated,
but we always want to show this in the big round,
those who are having an anniversary in the company, right?
And this time we have two, a 20s and a 15s, right?
The 15s we just did yesterday, the 20s for some time ago already.
So it's Jürgen.
stage 15 years in the company and it's uh from machine builder already 20 years thank you for
thank you for your contribution uh over the time i mean you have had the individual celebration
on this already um what i always wanted to say is that the thanks goes to you but it goes also
to everyone who is backing you up in your personal life because one can only contribute as strong as
you are contributing is there someone holding your back free it's a family
the family, the friends, whoever.
So please bring our regards to them as well
and extend this because they deserve a big thanks.
Thank you.
But we have more, 10 and 5 years, right?
Anyone here as well?
J-Bong, Moon-Gyu, I'm joining for Changwon,
John Jae-jin must be here, but maybe engineers.
It's fine.
I mean, that's the beauty of a virtual setting
and of a lot of offices in the world, right?
We are working globally and we can handle this.
So also big hand to the colleagues here, 5 and 10.
And for them, of course, we surely see them
at the 15th and 20th and 25th as well in this round here.
So thank you very much, colleagues.
But that's it.
now i would like to directly jump over from frank to stephanie and from stephanie to frank
you know in korea we in korea we're handing over things always like this right so it's my official
final handover of the clicker thank you thank you colleagues
Working? Yes, yeah.
There is more to come.
No, I will continue in English because otherwise everyone will look at me and say, what is she really saying?
First of all, before we're talking about Korea, let me really convey that big thanks to you.
I think what you did and we celebrated it yesterday, but also really a big thanks from
my side, not only on the partnership that we had together on the specific MTS business,
but also, and I think this is truly important and this will really help us also for the
years to come, the basis, the foundation that you build.
This is really exceptional.
And I think this is, for me, giving one of the best.
also how we then can start into the next fiscal year i think the numbers are showing it
and that's really a heartful thanks and for everything what you did you're not away
um you are at the other side of the of the planet um so to say and but i think still
um in our in our views and of course we are looking forward to grow the service part also
here in korea
To start also from my perspective on Korea, let me maybe start with really a small story.
And some of you have heard it already.
When I arrived here in Korea, what is like three weeks ago with my whole family, we had 20 bags.
know i have three children so we came in with 20 bags being there at the airport we thought okay
we we sorted out everything and finally then we arrived at home then my smallest son five years
old was super proud because my parents gave him a school bag because he started school and then he
was like where is my school bag and we were like we were looking everywhere and everyone was like
where's the school bag
you
And then we realized, oh, oh, we left it at the airport.
And I was like, oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
Two weeks later, I don't know how to figure that out.
This was like his preferred school bag.
So not like either one, but his preferred school bag.
And now comes my story.
Talking in Korean, I used a little bit of JetGPT still.
With the airport lost and found, I realized what Korea is able to do.
And I would never have thought about that.
But two days later, around midnight, I paid.
7,000. I put it in an envelope just in front of my door because then the delivery came around
midnight and then finally the school bag arrived again. And this is for me a small story of what
I have seen, how Korea treated me already super well. So that was a super nice first example,
but I think also on what's possible here.
And let me share some numbers with you.
You mentioned it.
Probably a quite good chance where we're standing
with all of the bases that have been built.
But I think Korea is not at the limit yet.
a lot of investment going in. You have seen the announcement with Samsung and SK Hinex,
what they're doing. $200 billion going into the manufacturing field.
20% also of the global semiconductors capacity coming out of Korea.
We are also, of course, using the semicons also from the other side in our own products.
But also Korea has 13 global 100 companies, also the innovation hubs going here.
I've seen the government announced you want to become number three in the AI market.
And this, of course, shows all across the industries that Korea is serving.
And for me, I read a lot about Korean history.
I think even of what you and the country did in the last 20 to 30 years is impressive.
think the question is now for me, how can we participate even more as Siemens Korea out of
that potential that the Korean market is giving us? The answer when you hear me talking is always
not too complicated. Because some of you know that I worked for our customers before. And the
most important thing for me is always that we think on what is the customer's problem that we want to solve.
We pointed it here, what does the customer need?
I still always like to talk about the problems because then you know what they really matter about.
It's not about a nice fancy technology, but the question is what really helps them to make a difference in the next step.
So this, you will hear me talk a lot about that because this for me is one of the key principles.
And Jung knows that with all of the verticals that we already exchanged about, of course, customers are in the center.
Second point, and this is, some of you already know that, this is for me also my personal ambition why I rejoined Siemens.
Because I believe that we are the only company that really can make that happen.
Because we have the software and the automation part.
We have the buildings and we have the automation part.
And by combining that together, there is no one competitor that we compete with.
if we pay our strength together.
And last but not least,
I think the question is then on the execution side
and that we of course need to do together
to win the opportunities and to do that as one team.
There is definitely, like, the next step to come.
And we selected already a proposal.
I hope I'm pronouncing it correctly.
Do-chak.
YAK, sorry, still learning, and you kind of nicely then translated it, because it is about
not only to continue the growth, but really to make a step change.
This is the idea.
And in the various dimensions to come from the market, really understand on what's necessary,
deep dive into the opportunities, then to really set up that growth engine, and of course,
to execute.
all of that together because the most important point and this is what we are here for we have
the technologies we have the products that are coming mostly from headquarters and what we can do
is depending on us there is nothing more of what we can do so
we can only continue and execute on that performance together
And this is what and why for me it really matters.
It's about you, it's about our customers, but it's also, of course, about how we capture that growth from a cultural perspective.
And we will do that as a team.
We will do that, of course, by questioning things, even at our customers.
Definitely we will also walk that through by each and every individual one of you.
I think you made a perfect foundation that we then can build on for the next couple of years.
And with that, I think the summary is quite short.
I think it's an amazing opportunity that we and the Korean market has.
I think we can only capture that together, together as Siemens.
And I'm now trying again the Korean saying.
Irragedueso, kibimnida.
Still learning, still learning.
Kamsahamnida.
Thank you, Stephanie.
So then I kindly invite Scott, Frank, Tino once again to the stage.
We have 10 minutes for the open discussions and Q&A session.
So, yeah, we have very insightful and very visionary presentations.
Also, thanking Tino and also welcoming Stephanie.
Very remarkable webcast, I would say, for today.
We can conclude it with great questions or some curiosity you used to have.
Also, I wanted to raise directly to Scott.
Please take the opportunity.
If anyone has some questions in mind, please raise your hand.
And also, Tim's colleagues, you can also join us in this conversation.
Any questions?
thank you
the first one
always gets a
pick-up clause
the second
we don't know